now there's one more lesson that we need
to talk about
and that is
a lesson on recursive formulas so let's
say if we have the formula
a of n plus one is equal to a of n
or rather three times a of n plus two
you need to know that a of n is the
previous term a of n plus one is an x
term
so let's say if the first term
is one
what is the value of
the next four terms
so if n is one n plus one is two
so the second term is three times the
value of the first term plus two
so three times one plus two which is
five
now if you want to find the third term
it's three times the second term plus
two
the second term is five
three times five is fifteen plus two is
seventeen
now if we wanna find the fourth term
it's three times the third term
plus two
the third term is seventeen
seventeen times three is fifty-one plus
two that's fifty-three so that's the
value of the fourth term
let's try another example
so let's say that a of n
is equal to two
times a of n minus one
and let's go ahead and square it
and then we'll subtract it by five
so a of n plus 1 was the next term a of
n was the previous term in this case
a of n minus 1 is the previous term a of
n is the next term
and let's say the first term
is equal to
two
so a of two is two times the square
of a of one minus five
so it's two times two squared minus five
two squared is four times two is eight
minus five that's three
a of three
is two times a of two
squared minus five
so a of two is three
three squared is nine
two times nine is eighteen eighteen
minus 5 is 13.
a sub 4
is 2 times the square of a sub 3 minus
5.
a sub 3 is 13
13 squared is 169
169 times 2
that's 338 minus 5
so this is equal to 333
and so that's how you can work with a
recursively defined formula
you